Being a Muslim, it's all about compassion. Like, I don't like to see people hurt. What I'm taught is that if I'm given blessings, I got to use every talent, every blessing that God gave me to alleviate harm and suffering. And that's what I do every day. And at least I think to myself, what can I do today to alleviate some of that harm and some of that suffering?
And sometimes it doesn't feel like I'm doing something major and transformative. But even if I'm doing something on a personal level, some form of kindness, something that is even beyond the organizing, just being a good person, that is a struggle for people, just to be a good, decent person.
Why is it so hard?
In this country, it's hard. You know why? Because, Amanda, we come from cultures, whether it's Black culture or different types of immigrant culture, where we're taught about this idea of a village.
This country taught us individualism. It taught me, you got health care, you got a job, don't worry about everybody else.
You got a house.
Better hear it out.
Yeah, you got a house.
They got bootstraps.
Yeah, why isn't the homeless man getting up and getting a job? So for me, like, I reject individualism.